# **NGUYEN TRONG HUY**

# Javascript Developer

+84 909291871

in linkedin.com/in/tronghuy229

huy.nguyen22994@gmail.com

👼 github.com/huynguyen22994



# **SUMMARY**

With more than 6+ experience in the Software Industry. I have experienced many technologies in both Font End and Back End such as NodeJs, AngularJS, ReactJS, React Native, etc... I am also proficient with Javascript and JSFrameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and user psychology.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Javascript

#### Frameworks/Platforms:

- o AngularJs, ReactJs, React Native, HTML, CSS
- o Nodejs, ExpressJs, Swagger, Sequelize, Socket
- o Jquery, Bootstrap, SCSS
- Gulp, Webpack/Babel

Database Management Systems: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Tools: Jira, Trello, Balsamia

Languages: Intermediate in English

#### Others:

- Hands-on experience with Cloud Computing Platforms: Heroku
- o Good understanding of Restful API. Have knowledge of Single Page Applications and Multi Page Applications
- Have knowledge of OOP, SOLID principles. And I can optimize performance, enhance UI/UX, propose tech.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack Developer & CO-Founder Chinta Viet Nam Co.,LTD

01/2020 -06/2023

**Project: Chinta Coffee** (Dev team is only me)

- Chinta is a startup. The startup operates in the field of F&B. My responsibility is developing these applications below to manage the coffee shops of Chinta, inclusions:
  - · Chinta POS: the web application allows staff to use with main functions: create invoices, inventory, shift reports...
  - <u>Chinta Merchant</u>: the web application allows store owners to use with main functions: manage revenue, manage staff, manage the shift of staff, manage salary, manage inventory, report ...
  - Chinta Staff: this web application allows staff to use with main functions: register the working schedule, view the working schedule, view salary ...
  - o Chinta Merchant Mini app: the mobile app allows store owners to use to view sales index report
  - Mobile app: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.chintavietnam.chintacoffee">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.chintavietnam.chintacoffee</a>

#### • Technologies:

- Front End: AngularJs, Bootstrap 4, Javascript, JQuery ...
- o Back End: NodeJs, ExpressJs, Swagger, Sequelize
- o Database: PostgreSQL
- Mobile App: React Native, Expo
- Cloud Computing Platforms: Heroku

# **Front End Developer**

#### TMA Solutions, Quang Trung Software City

07/2017 - 07/2019

Project: Omnivista Cirrus (the team more than 30 members)

• The project develops the system base on the web application to manage the network devices of customers from the USA

#### Technologies:

- Front End: AngularJs, Bootstrap 3, Stylus, Javascript (only use ES5)
- Implement proxy server by Nodejs

#### • Responsibilities:

- Implements new feature on demand through tasks on Jira
- Fixing bugs and enhancing features.
- Review code and help the project manager to mentor junior members of the UI team. Sometimes, I also refactor the code of junior members whom I mentor

#### • Others:

- Here, I got to join a Scrum team that uses the Alige Scrum software development process
- I joined the R&D team when I work here

#### Junior Javascript Developer

IMT Solutions, Tan Binh, Ho Chi Minh City

- 04/2017 06/2017
- In this company, I have joined a project which develop a website application used to rating images or videos by the
  users
- Technologies: Nodejs, ExpressJs, Swagger, MongoDB
- Responsibilities:
  - I have trained in Nodejs and modules of Nodejs
  - Fixing bugs
  - Implement a simple API gateway to CRUD

#### Internship

#### ISC-Quang Trung, Quang Trung Software City

12/2016 - 04/2017

- I got a training course about working processes (Agile and Scrum), soft skills, English writing & communication in working place and web development.
- I learned about creating a NodeJS server to provide the API, then using AngularJS on the Front-end side to display these data.
- Project: During the internship, I participated 2 projects
  - Project 1: Human management software center ISC.
    - Github: <a href="https://github.com/tienthanh2509/isc-node7">https://github.com/tienthanh2509/isc-node7</a>
  - Project 2: Caro game web app.
    - Github: https://github.com/minhducisc/gameCaro

#### PERSONAL PROJECT

FoodTech Shop 07/2019 - 11/2019

My wife and I opened a shop to sell noodles and I built a website to sell products and manage the shop

- Website: <a href="http://www.foodtechshop.vn">http://www.foodtechshop.vn</a>
- Github: https://github.com/huynguyen22994/YelaProject

# **EDUCATION**

#### **HUTECH University, Ho Chi Minh City**

2013 - 2018

Degree title: Information Technology Engineer

- Subjects included: Management System Database, Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Programming Techniques, Software Technology, Information Security, Project Management, Tools and Software Development Environment, Design, and Analysis Database
- The project below that I participated in when I was in school:
  - A website sell traveling clothes (ASP.NET MVC): <a href="http://huyvu.azurewebsites.net">http://huyvu.azurewebsites.net</a>

#### **INTERESTS**

- Reading Book
- Business
- Traveling
- · Research new knowledge